Nwachukwu Valentine Chigozie

Software Engineer

Mobile: +2348137245771 Address: PL 128 Oyadiran Estate Sabo Lagos GitHub: github.com/Justin-mario

E-mail: njchigozie@gmail.com Linkedln: www.linkedin.com/in/chigozie-valentine-nwachukwu-1123aa147

Personal Summary

I am a highly motivated and hardworking individual who switched career from hospitality and retail to software development two years ago, after completing a year-long techpreneurship program with Semi-Colon Africa a top IT training institute in Lagos Nigeria. I am currently Seeking to further my education in the United Kingdom. One of my life goals is to become a top software developer, tech enabling micro, small and medium sized businesses in Africa and finding solutions to numerous challenges confronting Africa. I enjoy reading, travelling and cooking.

Skills and Qualifications

- ✓ 1 Year experience with back-end development
- ✓ 3 months experience with front-end development
- ✓ Good knowledge of API & Database Design.

Tech Stack

Programming Languages: HTML5 | CSS | Java | JavaScript | Golang

Frameworks & Libraries: Springboot | Gin | React | JQuerry | Bootstrap

Databases: MySQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Others: Postman | Swagger | Figma | Canvas | Heroku | GIT GITHUB | Docker

Cloud Services: AWS Fundamentals | AZURE Fundamentals

Work History

Java Developer | RoadPadi

March 2022 - Present

Incharge of back-end development team

- ♦ Developed the back-end of a web and mobile application that helped users find nearest gas station with product
- ♦ Was part of a team that developed an web application that manages the operations of road transport company
- ♦ Was part of a team that build an infrastructure/platform that travel agents plug into to have access to trips of all transport companies on our platform and in so doing be able to sell tickets for them.

Java Developer Intern | ORSUL

October 2021 - March 2022

Worked with a team of developers building an application to connect artisans to customers in need of their services.

- Built a feature that sends an OTP to users and verifies same before on-boarding them.
- Developed the application security and JWT using spring security.
- ♦ Developed the on-boarding feature of the application for both artisans and their customers

Other Non Software Development Related Roles 2012 - 2020

Worked in Retail and Hospitality Industries

- ♦ Worked as a cashier with Bin Majid hotel in the United Arab Emirates for 3 years
- ♦ Worked as a tech support personnel in retail industry in Nigeria for 5 years.
- ♦ Details of all non software development roles will be provided on request

Education And Training

Semicolon Africa Techpreneurship Program

January 2021 - September 2021

Course Undertaken

- ✓ Design Thinking
- ✓ Critical Thinking
- ✓ Introduction to Industrial Design
- ✓ Java Programming
- ✓ HTML and CSS
- ✓ JavaScript
- ✓ Database Management with MYSQL and Microsoft SQL
- ✓ React
- ✓ Introduction to DevOps

IIHT

September 2020 - December 2020

Course Undertaken

✓ Introduction to cloud computing with Microsoft Azure

Anambra State University

September 2007 - February 2012

Course Undertaken

✓ Bachelor of Science Computer Science (second class upper)